

**TRINH DO** 

## **ABOUT ME**

With 5 years experiences in strategic planning and executing social campaigns, I can bring valuable insights and contribute effective marketing plan to drive a brand growth
I am seeking a Senior Account Executive position where my skills can be leveraged to achieve marketing objective

## INFORMATION



dlctrinh151@gmail.com



037 434 1599



Distric 8, HCM



1997

# SKILL

Social media (Facebook, TikTok)

Communication skill

English (TOIEC 660)

Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator)

Teamwork

Management project

Microsoft Office

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Economic Ho Chi Minh

2015 - 2019

Bachelor of International Bussiness

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **PUBLICIS GROUPE (MSL)**

**Account Executive** 

06/2021 - 5/2024

#### **CLIENTS:**

Skincare & beauty: Kiehl's Vietnam, Lancôme Vietnam

FMCG: Rong Do (URC); X-Men; X-Men For Boss; LASHE Superfood, Ôliv, Purité

**ACHIEVEMENT:** 

- Created #Kiehl's Calendura Glow TikTok challenge dance: 300M views in 1st week and ranked #2 in South East Asia across all markets in 2021. The Regional team provided all assets and materials, and I collaborated with the Planner and Creative teams to research and adapt ideas to suit the local market. At this time, TikTok was a new platform, so I maintained daily communication with TikTok and the Media team to review assets, set up ads, and build HCT page.
- Increased the Rong Do awareness to GenZ by establishing Rong Do official Tiktok account and creating HTC #TôChấtRiêng in 2022. I collaborated with the Social team to develop a plan for building the Rong Do TikTok account through HTC and Social Outreach. In this campaign, we introduced a new in-feed ads format with a Popup icon. I worked closely with the Brand, TikTok, and Media teams to understand this format and brainstormed with the Creative team to develop the assets. The results:
- Reaching 1,100M views and 340,1K video creation with #ToChatRieng challenge
  - RongDo Official Tiktok account: 30M Followers, 32M Like

**MEDIA PROJECTS EXECUTED:** SMC posts in Facebook and Instagram; TikTok videos; TikTok Hashtag Challenge; Facebook Minigames; Assets for E-commerce CPAS

- Worked with clients and the internal team to execute and optimize the media plans (Strategy, Creative/Content/Design, Media, Communication, Simple activation)
- · Managed the budget for total campaigns with effectively spends
- Ensured the timely and successful key delivery of campaigns, meeting the client expectations and deadlines
- Coordinated with the Planner team to research competitors, and topics trending on social. Developed Social AWO campaign X-Men strategies to positioning brands effectively targeting to GenZ (Built social always on content for X-Men fanpage to increase reach +21,6%, visit +118,5%, +2K user likes in Jul-Oct 2022)
- For Collaborated with the Media team to obtain and quality-check materials, ensuring following the material requests and the platform's safe zone guidelines
- Managed communication on media platforms to maintain positive interactions
- Developed and implemented minigames on social media platforms to increase brand awareness and user's engagement (Purité fanpage: reach +60,1%, visit +217,6% | Ôliv fanpage: reach +241,3%, visit +551,3%, +258 users like)
- Handled paperwork tasks including processing contracts, quotations, and liquidation projects.

## STARCOM

07/2019 - 03/2021

#### **Account PR Executive**

**CLIENT:** Samsung (TV & AD)

- Analyzed the effectiveness and relevance of various newspapers to develop strategic PR booking plans.
- Managed project timeline strictly under client's budget
- Worked directly with vendors (VCC, FPT, VNG,...) and newspapers to book articles and solve issues about content and words in article
- Supported performance team to manage and optimize Facebook SMC posts to gain the highest performance.

#### **LOTTE VIETNAM**

07/2018 - 09/2018

### **Merchandising Intern**

- Contacted and negotiated with sellers to make contracts
- Checked the order's ID and resolve problems
- Write copy and edit image to upload on Ecom website